Web Developer

James L. Lendrem

99 Park Avenue Newcastle Upon Tyne NE3 2LD United Kingdom Jamlendrem@gmail.com 07878426329

Self Motivated and Professional Web Developer.

Highly motivated professional Web Developer with over 4 years experience including experience working as the senior developer in a company. Projects worked on have been delivered in a time critical manner whilst helping clients increase sales and online conversion rates. Running a company for 2 years has given the ability to engage with clients in a respectful manner whilst getting a good understanding of a clients needs and expectations. Strong ability to optimise pre-existing websites using PHP and SQL to deliver speed increases greater than 50%. Object Orientated Programming experience in both PHP and Javascript as well as being a competent front-end developer working in HTML5 and CSS3.

Professional Experience

2015-today

Senior PHP Developer at Kino Creative.

Senior Developer at Kino Creative. Started off as the junior developer becoming the senior developer over the last two years. Worked on a wide variety of projects over the course of my employment for both small clients and larger clients.

- Developing Websites using PHP and Wordpress.
- Implementing Frontend Designs using HTML5, CSS3, and Sass.
- Engaging with clients to better understand their needs and help troubleshoot issues they encounter.
- Started learning Android to help move the company forward in another direction.

2013-2015

Co-Proprietor at Smooth Lines.

Founded and ran the business Smooth Lines in Hartlepool. We created websites for SMBs in Hartlepool giving companies professional websites for prices that they could afford.

- Developing Websites using PHP and Joomla.
- Day-to-day running of the business.
- Advertising the company by going to business events and selling websites to new clients.

Education

2010-2012

Computer Science at Newcastle University

Partially completed a Computer Science Degree at Newcastle University. Dropped out in my third year due to personal reasons.

- First Year First
- · Second Year First
- Third Year Incomplete

2008–2010 A-Levels at Brinkburn Sixth Form College

- Computing Science B
- · Mathematics C
- Physics D
- Further Mathematics AS

Projects

Kino Creative

Coastal Retreats - Company Website

After another developer left Kino Creative I took over the management and maintenance of this project. The client had a number of problems with search queries causing taking large amounts of time to return. It would also cause the site to hang during heavy usage. I successfully managed to analyse this and came to the conclusion database queries where causing the issue. After optimising the queries I reduced response times from 13 seconds to under half a second in most cases.

Kino Creative

Luxury Leisure – Online Training Resource

Successfully developed a online e-learning application for Luxury Leisure - the app was a single page application that allowed Luxury Leisure to train new employees in areas such as Food Safety, and under-age Gambling. It brought their training resources up to date and has successfully increased engagement with material that mostly went unread.

Kino Creative

Zespoke - WebGL Customiser

Created a 3D Customiser using WebGL for a client that sold bespoke furniture. The customiser allowed customers to see a visual representation of their chosen furniture. The customer could then change the colours of the table and add on options such as a glass shelf or table legs and this would be displayed on the visual representation. It also allows customers to move the table around to get a 360 degree view of the table. This has successfully increased engagement with the site.

Interests and Hobbies

- · Hackathons Ludum Dare and DevXS.
- Dungeons and Dragons (Roleplaying Games.)
- · Board Games.
- · Playing Guitar.
- Fantasy books.